Hello, and welcome back to another Ads Rx full ad sequence tutorial.
I'm Mark, and we're gonna dive into a commercial ad video.
Um, so we're gonna go through every little bit from pre-production,
all the way to editing. And so let's dive in.
This product is called Thera Ice Wrist Ice Pack. As you can see in this, uh,
image right there, it is a sleeve that slips over your wrist.
It both, uh,
can ice or cool or heat therapy warm. It,
um, goes in the freezer to cool it, put in the microwave to warm it up.
I'll get more into that right now actually.
So I visited their website and I can see the various different
products, uh, product benefits and features and such.
And so what I've gathered from all of this is that it
is a cold, flexible wrist ice pack.
It provides 360 degrees coverage around the hand for
ease of movement.
You can still use your wrist or your hands to do things like,
say, type on the computer, read a book, play on your phone, whatever it is.
Slip on design means no messy or uncomfortable. Ice packs, inserts, velcro,
awkward straps,
so obvious pain points slash comparison to other products that
you could use for the same kind of problems. Uh,
this is cleaner, easier, less messy, all of that. Um,
it can be worn comfortably on both hands,
so it's just kind of one size fits all one, uh,
you'll only need one for either hand, whatever. Um,
it's reusable. And, uh, let's see, what else? Um, so again,
the hot and cold therapy angles pretty cool.
It's unique that it can be used for either. The material is, uh,
very interesting. It's kind of like a neoprene, uh,
like a wetsuit material. Um,
but it has this gel inside that adapts to whatever the co the, uh,
temperature is. So it's, it's warm or cool. It's very stretchable.
It's one piece so that, uh,
it's not tearing up the seams and it form fits to your wrist pretty well.
Honestly, I was wearing one the other day, wasn't complaining,
so I went ahead. I went through there and I started scripting it out.
And so my primary goal while scripting this video out was
to bring awareness to the product and its features, obviously,
but also to look nice. Uh, you know, we want it to be really relatable.
This is a commercial. It's not, um,
it's not a viral ad. It's not U G C.
So we wanted to go for a slow, slower paced,
elegant look throughout the whole video so that it, it, it looks clean,
it looks nice, it's enticing to the viewer, but it,
but it's also selling the product. And, you know,
maybe you can see yourself in this lifestyle footage. Like, you know,
this is what I wanna strive for in life, is to be this person, you know,
wearing this and this cool house in California.
So as I was writing out the script,
I wanted to figure out a way to implement every different element of the product
features and benefits and so on, while also, again, keeping it engaging, um,
and carry it through with a voiceover that's simple and
elegant. The same thing. Everything is simple and elegant,
and I'll get to shooting style, but we,
we just reiterate that throughout the whole process from shooting to editing,
all of that. So, as we're going through, um,
I was writing out the voiceover, so, you know,
some sort of a hook at the beginning just to catch the attention. Um,
easy kind of split screen, painful wrist product on the wrist. Uh, for me,
I play guitar. And so from this, uh,
function as well as typing on the computer all day,
obviously my wrist very sensitive. So the idea of a pushup, um,
sometimes when I'll do a pushup, it just starts hurting immediately in my wrist.
This product is perfect for that. So pain point of painful wrist,
and then putting the product on introduction shot.
Wanna get straight to the point, make sure they know what their,
what the viewer is watching and what this product is.
Then we move on. It's a new way to get soothing relief. It's small, lightweight,
and easy to wear. Start introducing its benefits and,
and a little bit of hype to it. You know, it's exciting. It's new,
it's something brand new. Um, expert grade gel liner. Soft,
breathable fabric won't irritate your skin. Again,
we're just throwing out the different benefits so that, uh,
you can keep absorbing it. As you're watching this nice footage,
as you're watching this engage in video,
you're getting the reasons over and over again the reasons why you should pick
up this product. Um, again,
360 degrees of comfort and the shots that I'd scripted out
are all meant to obviously, uh,
explain the voiceover or, um,
validate what the voiceover is saying. Um, so then we move on.
So you can enjoy soothing relief while doing your normal activities.
This is probably the biggest line in the whole thing. Um,
it's totally relatable. People are on their phone, the computer book,
reading a book, lounging on the couch, whatever it is. This says,
you don't have to ruin your day. You don't have to stop doing what you're doing.
Just put this on. It'll help you. It'll, you know, it'll make,
it'll give you relief. Uh, also with this particular product, um,
uh, there were, there were some issues.
We had to make sure to keep everything broad,
not make any extreme claims that can't be, uh, held up.
So we, we use the word relief a lot. Instead of, uh, you know, know,
treating the symptom of pain, it's relieving you, it's giving soothing relief,
whatever. Um, and for heated relief, place it in the microwave.
That's a cool alternate that probably most viewers aren't expecting.
Then, uh, a comparison. Again, no more messy, uncomfortable ice packs,
talent stretching the product or putting it on, you know, whatever. Um,
logically too, you could show a pain point of uncomfortable,
messy ice packs. We've done that in the past, plus it's small.
You can take it anywhere with you, um, logical extra,
uh, feature to it or an extra benefit. It is small,
so you can easily put it in the gym bag after you work out at the gym.
You can slip it right on, drive home wearing it, um,
some social proof just to hammer it in. So we've got hundreds of,
uh, hundreds of thousands of people are experiencing relief with Thera Ice, um,
with a review overlay. And, uh, that way the viewer sees,
oh, look, other people like me are doing it. It's real, it's validated.
It's not just some online product that they're lying to me about.
These are real people, real, uh, reviews.
And then close it out with the c t a experience,
soothing relief with the Thera Ice wrist pack. So, um,
thera Ice Wrist Ice pack, excuse me. So yeah,
so we scripted this out and then we went to shoot it,
and when it came time to shoot it, um,
we have a nice camera and, uh,
we wanted to really go for an elegant lifestyle. Look,
we rented a space here in southern California, a very nice open,
um, house with lots of, lots of room,
lots of natural light coming in, lots of big windows, and, uh,
just a kind of cool interior design, um,
which leaned into this lifestyle, uh, vibe that we were going for.
And so,
to a company that we wanted to do really smooth motion,
really dynamic shots, just look as cinematic as possible.
We shot everything at 120 frames per second so that we could slow it down.
Um, because again, we want this to be relieving,
uh, as a video, the video is soothing. It, it, uh,
reinforces the selling point of the product itself,
which is that it is soothing. So we shot it, um,
lot, again, lots of slow motion, lots of, uh,
we did a little bit of handheld or motion, uh, tripod on wheels,
but just get smooth tracking shots, rotating shots,
some panning, all of that just to, uh,
make it look nice while again,
getting these specific shots that validate the voiceover, that,
that tell the narrative of the video. But doing it in an elegant way.
We actually wound up to, um, uh,
putting our light outside the window so that we could get light coming through
the window, uh, extra natural light coming through the window,
which was really cool. Um, so it,
that little extra bit of effort in production or in pre-production with the
script, at whatever point it is, that little bit of extra effort,
it makes a very big difference when it comes to, uh,
really elevating your final product. Doing it in,
in the beginning, doing it in each stage, it shows in the end.
So then let's dive into Premier.
So once we got that together, we started to,
uh, roll through the edit, pulling out all of my different shots, um,
like to organize everything in a way that I can access it easily.
So I like to do bins like, uh,
I like to do bins like this.
Everybody has their own method for organization when it comes to inside
premier. Personally for me, I like graphics, music, raw sequences,
and ss f x for sound effects. Um,
anything else can add or whatever works for you really,
but inside my sequences is, uh,
it's always easy to find my specific sequence for this,
or if they're different variations, some videos have different hooks, whatever.
Um, it's easy to access those. Then my raws, same thing.
I I never wanna have to go looking when I need a specific shot,
and I don't want to count on knowing exactly what the file name is called in
searching it. So I wanna find everything easily.
So the raws are organized by different types. Um, you know,
there's the couple having a conversation. Um,
this is them. They're sitting next to each other,
both wearing the wrist pack, see them having the conversation.
This is putting the microwave and in the freezer we've got pain points over
here, wrist hurting,
messy ice pack, or, you know, annoying Velcro.
So on some shots of putting it on. And,
um, we've got the guy playing video games while wearing it,
woman on the laptop wearing while wearing it. Again,
the general premise of this video is going to be using that narrative, um,
or that voiceover, and then reinforcing it with footage that looks nice,
but goes along with it. And so now we get into the edit itself. I,
my process was going through this right here is the voiceover.
So I went through and I took,
I cut up the voiceover so that it was moving at a decent pace. Um,
a lot of the times the voiceovers come in, they'll be, uh, too slow,
or not even that they're too slow,
but they'll put pauses in between the lines to give us the op, uh, editors,
the opportunity to cut them together in a better way, uh, which is helpful. So,
cut that up, lined it up, and then started just grabbing shots, um,
that went with it, but also predominantly where the,
the shots that I scripted out we shot according to that. So that worked out.
And then an important thing is I slowed virtually every
shot down. Um, same thing, like we were saying,
we want the video to give off a
relieving, a soothing vibe.
And so just like the product does, just to reinforce the product.
So in order to do that, everything should be really,
really gentle and smooth. And so there, there isn't anything too fast. The,
the captions don't just pop on, they transition on, uh,
the footage isn't just moving like crazy.
I slowed it down all the way down to 30% on some things you'll see right now.
But it creates this totally, uh, different experience as a viewer.
So
See, everything's slow.
The pacing is different when you put that in with some music,
you know, gentle enough music that's doing it slowly soothing.
So another important thing is we shot this entire
video in, uh, slog. We have a Sony FX three camera,
um, and we shot in Slog three, which is a raw format.
And what that means is if I open up Lumetri color and turn it
off, that's what the raws look like in reality. So
I downloaded a, uh, a lut, which is a,
uh, color correction preset, and then from there, corrected it further.
Um, you can also, uh, you, you can create it yourself.
Do a, um, a grading yourself,
just using curves and basic correction, anything that you want.
It's really easy to use a, uh, lot.
And I've also actually created a few different custom lots for Slog three.
It does depend on what raw format you're using. There's slog three,
there's Slog two, and these are just Sony's raws. Everybody else has others. So,
um, whatever it is that you're working with. That being said,
shooting in a raw format like this did,
does give us the ability to have way more control into, uh,
the end color grading results. So I really like the color on this.
It's really ultra realistic. There was a,
a lot of natural sunlight coming in. We got a little bit of the,
that yellow warm tone to it,
but without it overwhelming everything else and just looking like a Sia tone or
something. So, um, I went through and applied,
uh, uh, basically clip by clip each thing.
So this one without lumetri, right, it's, it's almost, it's,
it's a little jarring looking until you correct it, and then it, it just works.
Um, it's surprising how much information is in there. Like,
take this one for example, turn that on,
and then once you put the correction on, there's just,
there's so much color in there, you don't expect it to be so nice looking,
but it is. So, um, yeah, let's keep it moving.
Um,
from there I added some soothing music and then some sound effects.
And, uh, like I mentioned before, all of the caption design,
we made sure that all of them had animations on them, some type of animation.
So nothing is just jarring sudden, you know,
just there everything is, uh,
catering to that soothing effect.
And again, starting it with get soothing relief. Now, it's a catchy hook.
It's something that people relate to. I was saying, I play guitar.
Other people have, for whatever reason,
whether it's being on the computer too long,
whatever people's wrists hurt over time.
People experience pain over time, the, the older you get.
And so right out the gate we're hitting them with, you have this problem,
I have this problem, people have this problem. This is how you get the relief.
And we're looking at
one sec, just over one second, and we're introducing the product
Again. People see themselves in this type of lifestyle.
Regular footage like this, he's playing a video game.
How many people play video games? Also fun. No, on that video games doing too,
ma playing too many video games can hurt your hand. They can hurt your wrist.
And, uh, also the way that it goes, the product it goes, um,
your thumb slips through it, so it will hit this muscle here too.
So the use cases that we're showing in this video are things
that would logically benefit from this product.
So that's kind of the general narrative of the whole thing.
Get soothing relief while doing your normal activities. So again,
that's why we're gonna reinforce that narrative throughout with,
with all of these examples of doing normal things and wearing the product and
getting that soothing relief while also showing it in a soothing,
relieving way of slow,
elegant footage and transitions.
So again, it is a different product, as they said, it's a new product,
a new way to treat this particular, uh, symptom.
And so therefore this video does have to be somewhat informative while
selling the product and giving the, the features and benefits.
We do need to say, you know,
you put it in the microwave or you put it in the freezer. That's how it works.
There's your comparison, pain point shots right there.
That extra extra feature at the end. It's so small.
You put in your gym bag
and there's our extras,
our social proof at the end so that people can feel like, oh, okay, it's real.
People really like it, it seems to be popular. You know,
it's just like when you go on Amazon and you're trying to buy something and
you're sorting through things with the highest reviews,
or this one only has five, can't be good. Whatever it may be. This product,
uh, this, uh, social proof section,
it just validates everything you've watched before to really close in on that
final C T A.
And then there it is,
client liked the winky and bear, uh, animation at the end.
So we closed out with that. And, um, yeah, so that,
that's really the gist of this, this sequence. It's pretty straightforward.
I came in at the end, um, and added these sound effects.
I just personally,
I think I like when there is an animation of any type,
be it text or transitions or any type of, uh,
any type of graphic animation. I, I wanna hear something that goes with it.
But again, this is a soothing video. I don't want that to be, uh,
distracting or fast or jarring or anything other than adding
to the value of the video. So I've got very, very subtle little,
uh, push and swoosh whoosh noises going on.
So that's the faster one for the push.
And then that's this gentle one, uh, for the sound, um,
for the, uh, text, uh, graphics. And then,
um, you know, we have an audio library. Uh,
hopefully you've grabbed it for me. I keep this thing open.
I pull out any of these, uh, sound effects that I need for any given moment.
I definitely use the whooshes probably the most, if not, um,
it depends on the type of video, but some of them, you know,
I'll dive deeper much deeper on it, especially if there's comedy involved.
But for this particular video, just use these two right here, simple.
And then, uh, again, when you're picking the music for a video,
you want it to reinforce whatever, again,
whatever the narrative of your video is.
Every video needs to have some sort of a narrative.
It doesn't mean you're literally telling a story. Um,
it doesn't mean it's just a voiceover telling the story,
but there's a point to your video, there's a point to your sequence.
Like I just said, we came with this, uh,
elegant visuals to introduce a product and carry you through the process
of informing you of what the product is, what the problem is that it's fixing,
and, uh, every little benefit and feature that goes along with that.
Reinforced it with, again,
a comparison to the other products out there and why this is so much better.
And then reinforced it further with social proof, uh, testimonial reviews,
showing that people are loving it, it's good product,
you should check it out and then close it out with the C T A,
which in this case, because it's just a commercial ad, is just the product.
There's no direct call to action. They're not saying, go buy this.
This product is like, all right, we just sold you on this video. Again,
it's the Thera Ice Risk Ice pack.
Now you might be on their Amazon page already on the listing for this or on
their website, and you just needed that extra little push at the end.
This was that extra little push. And then you just go and you click, click buy.
So when it comes to the music, I wanna further that narrative.
I want it to be calm, soothing, professional,
but not too professional, not cheesy.
It's just kind of giving you the general vibe,
some background to further everything else that you're doing with the,
with the voiceover, with the visuals, with the editing style.
So I also like when,
when the music really kicks in, when it hits introducing,
so it's got that swell and then there, ice wrist, ice pack, boom.
Again, these are all unrealistically slow motions,
which just feel really, uh, elegant and lifestyle, like
some simple dissolved transitions. Sometimes it can be that simple.
It doesn't have to be complicated.
Animations and such can just dissolve between a clip. It looks clean.
And then I always like to, uh, bring the music up as soon as the voiceover ends.
Don't go so much that it's surprising. And again, jarring,
especially with this particular video. We wanna keep things calm and relieving.
Um, but, you know, don't let it just dwindle out. Um,
so I'll, I'll bring the music up, go to the c t a,
and then fade the music down here with this transition. Um, also, of course,
always make sure, uh, I removed them, for example.
But always make sure to put cross fades on your audio.
So easy way to do that.
Highlight all of the cuts on your voiceover and hit if you're on a
Mac command shift D and you're good to go believe if it's a pc,
it's uh, control shift D and uh,
that applies your preset.
So if you go into settings timeline,
you can change the audio transition, default duration.
I like to keep it really small for this exact reason. So two frames.
Video transition,
duration I change often depending on what project I'm working on and what it is
I'm looking for. This is a slow transition, uh,
which is good for this particular product. Um, so you can set it there,
highlight all your audio command,
shift D and now you've just protected yourself from any pops, any clicks.
Make smooth transitions between shots. And then, um,
you know, with your, uh, video transitions, depends on what it is.
But say I wanted to push, you could right click on it,
set it as your default,
and then as soon as you hit command D or control D, if you're on a windows,
uh,
it'll apply that transition that you just set in the amount of frames that you
just set as well for 20 frames. So that's about it.
Hope you've enjoyed the tutorial and I hope you find it valuable and you're able
to implement this into your videos. And, uh, I will see you next time.